Guide to the William Hane Wannamaker Papers, 1917 - 1948 UA.05.52.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William H. Wannamaker papers
1917 - 1948
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Wannamaker, William Hane, 1873-
UA.05.52.0001
14 Linear Feet
William Hane Wannamaker (1873-1958) was a professor and administrator at Trinity College and Duke University for over four decades. He served as Dean of Trinity College and Vice President for the Educational Division, and was responsible for critical decisions regarding student, faculty, and administrative policies. The William H. Wannamaker Papers are the official files of the Dean and Vice President of Trinity College and Duke University. Materials include correspondence, reports, evaluations, and other administrative materials. Major subjects include student discipline, faculty issues, World Wars I and II, college sports, the hiring and promotion of faculty, and other administrative matters. English.
14000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Provenance
The William Hane Wannamaker Papers were received as a transfer in 1972 and 1973.
Biographical Note
William Hane Wannamaker was born September 28, 1873 in Bamberg, South Carolina. He attended Wofford College, Spartanburg, S.C., and received the A.B. degree in 1895. He worked as a school principal for several years, then in 1900, his former professor at Wofford, Trinity President John C. Kilgo, encouraged him to come to Trinity College, Durham, N.C., as instructor in English and graduate student. He received the A.M. degree from Trinity in 1901. He studied at Harvard University, earning an A.M. there in 1902, and completed additional study at several universities in Germany.
He returned to Trinity College as a professor of German language and literature in 1905. In 1910, another former professor from Wofford, William P. Few, became president at Trinity, and Wannamaker became a member of the college's administrative committee. In 1917, he received a Litt.D. degree from Wofford College. In the same year he was named Dean of Trinity College. After Trinity College became Duke University, Wannamaker remained as Dean and became Vice President for the Educational Division in 1926, a post he held until he retired in 1948. According to historian Robert F. Durden, "Wannamaker held the primary responsibility (along with President Few) for faculty recruitment and development--a large task in a rapidly expanding, new research university."
In addition to his academic administrative duties, Wannamaker chaired the Athletic Committee at Duke. He also served on the Board of Education of the City of Durham for 24 years, and was chairman of this board from 1925 to 1947. Wannamaker was also a Trustee of Watts Hospital and a Rotarian.
After his retirement, Wannamaker was named Vice-Chancellor, a title he held until his death in Pine Bluff, N.C., on August 2, 1958. Wannamaker is buried in Maplewood Cemetery, Durham, N.C. Wannamaker married Isabel Stringfellow of Chester, S.C., on June 30, 1903. They had four children: Margaret Elizabeth, William Hane, Isabel, and Harriet Foote. Isabel Stringfellow Wannamaker died in November 1957.
Collection Overview
The William H. Wannamaker Papers are the official files of the Dean and Vice President of Trinity College and Duke University. The first series, Correspondence, covers the period of Wannamaker's tenure in those positions, 1917-1948, and is arranged chronologically. Topics include student discipline, faculty issues, World Wars I and II, and other administrative concerns. The second series, Personnel, concerns the recruitment and development of the faculty for the years 1930 to 1948, and is arranged chronologically. Faculty appointments and promotions at all levels are included, as are the reports of departmental chairs. The third series, Subject Files, consists of a variety of materials related to Duke University, such as committee and council reports, and reports to the President. It is organized alphabetically.
Related Material
Kilgo (John C.) Records and Papers, 1888-1970 (bulk 1894-1920)
Duke University Archives
Few (William P.) Records and Papers, 1814-1971 and undated (bulk 1911-1940)
Duke University Archives
William Henry Glasson papers, 1891-1946 and undated
Duke University Archives
William Hane Wannamaker, Biographical File
Duke University Archives
World War, 1914-1918 -- Education and the war; World War, 1939-1945 -- Education and the war; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University -- History; Duke University -- Administration; Wannamaker, William Hane, 1873-; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Administration; Wannamaker, William Hane, 1873-; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Faculty; Duke University -- Sports; Duke University -- Students; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Students; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- History
- Correspondence, 1917-1948
  Scope and Contents note
  This Correspondence series covers the complete period of Wannamaker's tenure as Dean and Vice President, 1917-1949. He was involved in many administrative, faculty, and student issues. It is arranged chronologically. Most of the letters are copies of Wannamaker's outgoing correspondence. Topics include the discipline of students, the effect of World War I and World War II on students and college life, the recruitment and hiring of new faculty and staff, the inquiries of potential students, athletics issues (the Faculty Committee on Athletics), and the Board of Education of the City of Durham, of which Wannamaker was Chairman.
  Some personnel and student information may be contained in this series; records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years. In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
  - September 1917-December 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - January 1918-May 1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - June 4, 1918-April 23, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - May 4, 1919-September 13, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - October 1919-January 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - February 1920-March 1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - April 1920-July 1920 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - August 1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - September 1920-November 1920 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - December 1920-March 1921 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - April 1921-June 21, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - June 23, 1921-September, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - October 1921-December 1921 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - January 1922-April 1922 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - May 1922-July 7, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - July 10, 1922-August, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - September 1922-December 1922 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - January 1923-March 1923 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - April 1923-June 1923 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - July 1923 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - August 1923-September 1923 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - October 1923-November 1923 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - December 1923-February 1924 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - March 1924-April 1924 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - May 1924-June 1924 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - July 1, 1924-August 13, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - August 14, 1924-November 7, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - November 8, 1924-November 29, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - December 1924-February 1925 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - March 1925-May 1925 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - June 1925-October 1925 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - November 1925-February 1926 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - March 1926-May 14, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - May 17, 1926-July 1926 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - August 1926-October 20, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - October 21, 1926-December 1926 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - January 1927-February 1927 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - March 1927-April 11, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - April 12, 1927-May 14, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - May 16, 1927-June 10, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - June 11, 1927-June 30, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - July 1927 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - August 1927 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - September 1927-October 1927 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - November 1927-December 1927 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - January 1928-February 1928 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - March 1928 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - April 3, 1928-May 15, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - May 17, 1928-December 1928 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - January 1929-December 1929 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - January 1930-May 1930 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - July 1930-December 1930 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - January 1931-April 1931 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - May 1931-September 1931 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - October 1931-November 2, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - November 3, 1931-December 10, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - December 11, 1931-December 31, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - January 1932 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - February 1932 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - March 1932-April 27, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - April 28, 1932-May 1932 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - June 1932-July 22, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - July 23, 1932-August 1932 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - September 1932 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - October 1932 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - November 1932 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - December 1932-January 16, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - January 17, 1933-January 31, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - February 1, 1933-February 21, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - February 22, 1933-March 31, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - April 1, 1933-May 15, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - May 16, 1933-June 8, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - June 9, 1933-June 30, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - July 1, 1933-August 28, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - August 29, 1933-September 30, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - October 1933-November 1933 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - December 4, 1933-December 31, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - January 5, 1934-April 18, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - April 20, 1934-June 29, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - July 1934-October 1934 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - November 1934-December 1934 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - January 1935-March 15, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - March 21, 1935-May 31, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - June 1935-September 15, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - September 18, 1935-November 29, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - December 1935-January 1936 (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 86-87)
  - February 3, 1936-March 16, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - March 17, 1936-April 23, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - April 25, 1936-May 29, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - June 6, 1936-September 28, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - September 29, 1936-November 9, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - November 10, 1936-November 30, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - December 1, 1936-December 18, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - December 19, 1936-January 29, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - February 1937 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - March 1, 1937-March 5, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - March 6, 1937-April 13, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - April 14, 1937-May 3, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - May 6, 1937-May 31, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - June 1937 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - July 1937-August 1937 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - September 1937 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - October 1937 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - November 1, 1937-November 23, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - November 24, 1937-December 1937 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - January 1938-March 14, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - March 15, 1938-April 30, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - May 1938 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - June 1938-July 1938 (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - August 1, 1938-September 21, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - September 22, 1938-October 14, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - October 15, 1938-October 31, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - November 1, 1938-November 25, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - November 28, 1938-December 4, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - December 5, 1938-December 14, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - December 15, 1938-January 16, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - January 17, 1939-February 13, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - February 14, 1939-March 10, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - March 11, 1939-March 30, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - April 1, 1939-May 9, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - May 10, 1939-May 31, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - June 1939 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - July 6, 1939-September 1939 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - October 2, 1939-November 9, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - November 10, 1939-November 30, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - December 1, 1939-December 18, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - December 19, 1939-December 31, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - January 2, 1940-January 16, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - January 17, 1940-January 31, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - February 1, 1940-February 14, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - February 15, 1940-February 29, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - March 1, 1940-April 5, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - April 8, 1940-May 21, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - May 22, 1940-July 31, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - August 2, 1940-September 30, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - October 3, 1940-November 14, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - November 15, 1940-November 30, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - December 1, 1940-December 26, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 139)
  - January 2, 1941-February 12, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 140)
  - February 13, 1941-February 28, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - March 3, 1941-April 20, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - April 21, 1941-May 31, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - June 2, 1941-August 28, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - September 1, 1941-October 31, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - November 1941 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - December 1941 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - January 1942 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - February 1942 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - March 1942 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - April 1942-May 1942 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - June 1942-August 18, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - August 20, 1942-September 1942 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - October 2, 1942-October 27, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - October 28, 1942-November 1942 (Box 13, Folder 155)
  - December 1942-January 1943 (Box 14, Folder 156)
  - February 1943 (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - March 1943 (Box 14, Folder 158)
  - April 1, 1943-May 6, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 159)
  - May 7, 1943-May 31, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - June 1, 1943-July 5, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - July 6, 1943-July 29, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - August 2, 1943-September 8, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 163)
  - September 9, 1943-October, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 164)
  - November 1, 1943-December 15, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 165)
  - December 16, 1943-January 31, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 166)
  - February 1944-March 1944 (Box 15, Folder 167)
  - April 3, 1944-April 20, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - April 21, 1944-May 31, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 169)
  - June 1, 1944-June 24, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 170)
  - June 26, 1944-July 30, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 171)
  - August 2, 1944-October 7, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 172)
  - October 9, 1944-October 31, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 173)
  - November 3, 1944-December 31, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 174)
  - January 1945-February 1945 (Box 15, Folder 175)
  - March 1, 1945-April 10, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 176)
  - April 11, 1945-May 30, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 177)
  - June 4, 1945-July 21, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 178)
  - July 23, 1945-August 31, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 179)
  - September 1, 1945-October 10, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 180)
  - October 11, 1945-November 8, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 181)
  - November 9, 1945-November 30, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 182)
  - December 3, 1945-January 10, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 183)
  - January 11, 1946-February 28, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 184)
  - March 1946-April 4, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 185)
  - April 5, 1946-April 30, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 186)
  - May 1, 1946-May 15, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 187)
  - May 16, 1946-May 30, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 188)
  - June 4, 1946-June 24, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 189)
  - June 25, 1946-July 15, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 190)
  - July 16, 1946-July 31, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 191)
  - August 1, 1946-August 22, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 192)
  - August 23, 1946-September 28, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 193)
  - September 30, 1946-October 31, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 194)
  - November 1946 (Box 17, Folder 195)
  - December 1946 (Box 17, Folder 196)
  - January 2, 1947-January 16, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 197)
  - January 17, 1947-January 20, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 198)
  - January 21, 1947-February 13, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 199)
  - February 14, 1947-March 10, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 200)
  - March 11, 1947-April 5, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 201)
  - April 7, 1947-April 30, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 202)
  - May 1, 1947-May 27, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 203)
  - May 28, 1947-June 30, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 204)
  - July 1, 1947-July 28, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 205)
  - July 30, 1947-August 30, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - September 1, 1947-October 21, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 207)
  - October 22, 1947-November 19, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 208)
  - November 20, 1947-December 16, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 209)
  - December 17, 1947-January 21, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 210)
  - January 22, 1948-February 28, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 211)
  - March 1, 1948-March 23, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 212)
  - March 24, 1948-April 15, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 213)
  - April 16, 1948-April 30, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 214)
  - May 1, 1948-May 14, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 215)
  - May 15, 1948-May 31, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 216)
  - June 1, 1948-June 9, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 217)
  - June 10, 1948-July 30, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 218)
  - August 2, 1948-October 9, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 219)
  - October 11, 1948-November 30, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 220)
  - December 1948 (Box 19, Folder 221)
- Personnel, 1929-1948
  The Personnel series includes correspondence detailing the hiring and promotion of Duke University faculty and staff during Wannamaker's tenure. The Appointments subseries includes both new hires and promotions. The Salary Schedules subseries includes information about department budget allocations, as well as individual faculty members' salaries.
  Because this series contains personally identifiable information, it is restricted; please contact the University Archives for more information.
  - Appointments
    - 1929-April 1931 (Box 19, Folder 222)
    - May 1, 1931-October 14, 1931 (Folder 223, Box 20)
    - January 5, 1932-March 8, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 224)
    - March 10, 1932-December 10, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 225)
    - April 12, 1933-May 23, 1934 (Box 20, Folder 226)
    - May 24, 1934-December 31, 1934 (Box 20, Folder 227)
    - January 12, 1935-March 31, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 228)
    - April 1, 1935-June 29, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 229)
    - July 10, 1935-July 31, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 230)
    - August 1, 1935-August 21, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 231)
    - August 22, 1935-December 31, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 232)
    - January 4, 1936-March 31, 1936 (Box 20, Folder 233)
    - April 1, 1936-May 5, 1936 (Box 20, Folder 234)
    - May 7, 1936-May 29, 1936 (Box 20, Folder 235)
    - June 1, 1936-July 31, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 236)
    - August 3, 1936-December 23, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 237)
    - January 5, 1937-February 18, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 238)
    - February 19, 1937-April 13, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 239)
    - April 14, 1937-May 31, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 240)
    - June 1, 1937-July 24, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 241)
    - July 27, 1937-December 8, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 242)
    - January 12, 1938-March 8, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 243)
    - March 10, 1938- April 28, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 244)
    - April 30, 1938-May 31, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 245)
    - June 1, 1938-October 6, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 246)
    - October 10, 1938-February 28, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 247)
    - March 1, 1939-May 11, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 248)
    - May 12, 1939-June 30, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 249)
    - July 1, 1939-July 21, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 250)
    - August 1939-December 1939 (Box 22, Folder 251)
    - February 1940-May 1940 (Box 22, Folder 252)
    - June 1940-July 1940 (Box 22, Folder 253)
    - August 1940-December 1940 (Box 22, Folder 254)
    - January 1941-March 1941 (Box 22, Folder 255)
    - April 1941-May 1941 (Box 22, Folder 256)
    - June 1941-July 18, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 257)
    - July 21, 1941-August 1941 (Box 22, Folder 258)
    - September 1941-January 1942 (Box 23, Folder 259)
    - February 1942-May 1942 (Box 23, Folder 260)
    - June 1942-July 8, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 261)
    - July 9, 1942-July 31, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 262)
    - August 1, 1942-August 14, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 263)
    - August 15, 1942-September 30, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 264)
    - October 1942-February 1943 (Box 23, Folder 265)
    - March 1943-May 1943 (Box 23, Folder 266)
    - June 1943-July 14, 1943 (Box 23, Folder 267)
    - July 15, 1943-August 1943 (Box 23, Folder 268)
    - September 1943-November 10, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 269)
    - November 11, 1943-January 1944 (Box 24, Folder 270)
    - February 1944-March 1944 (Box 24, Folder 271)
    - April 1944-May 1944 (Box 24, Folder 272)
    - June 1944-July 19, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 273)
    - July 20, 1944-September 1944 (Box 24, Folder 274)
    - October 1944-December 1944 (Box 24, Folder 275)
    - January 1945-March 7, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 276)
    - March 8, 1945-May 1945 (Box 24, Folder 277)
    - June 1945 (Box 25, Folder 278)
    - July 1945 (Box 25, Folder 279)
    - August 2, 1945-August 18, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 280)
    - August 20, 1945-August 31, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 281)
    - September 4, 1945-October 2, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 282)
    - October 3, 1945-October 30, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 283)
    - November 1945-December 1945 (Box 25, Folder 284)
    - January 1946-February 1946 (Box 25, Folder 285)
    - March 1946-May 15, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 286)
    - May 16, 1946-June 1946 (Box 25, Folder 287)
    - July 1946-August 1946 (Box 26, Folder 288)
    - September 1946-March 1947 (Box 26, Folder 289)
    - April 1947-June 18, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 290)
    - June 21, 1947-August 1947 (Box 26, Folder 291)
    - September 1947-May 1948 (Box 26, Folder 292)
  - Salary Schedules
    - March 16, 1946-January 31, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 293)
    - February 1947-November 1947 (Box 26, Folder 294)
    - 1948 (Box 26, Folder 295)
- Subject File, 1926-1946
  The Subject File series contains information about a number of Duke University offices and organizations. It mainly includes correspondence and reports, including President's Reports. The series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Alumni Office, Duke University, circa 1934-1937 (Box 26, Folder 296)
  - Cameron Indoor Stadium, Duke University, circa 1940 (Box 26, Folder 297)
  - Classroom Capacities, Duke University, undated (Box 26, Folder 298)
  - Committees and Councils, 1936-1939 (Box 26, Folder 299)
  - Committees and Councils, 1940-1946 (Box 26, Folder 300)
  - Curriculum Committee, Duke University, undated (Box 26, Folder 301)
  - Degree Requirements, Duke University, undated (Box 26, Folder 302)
  - Educational Research Committee, Duke University, 1935 (Box 27, Folder 303)
  - Ellwood, Charles Abram, undated (Box 27, Folder 304)
  - Graduate School, Duke University, undated (Box 27, Folder 305)
  - Guidance Office, Duke University, undated (Box 27, Folder 306)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review, undated (Box 27, Folder 307)
  - Miscellany, circa 1926-1940 (Box 27, Folder 308)
    Includes information about distribution of grades in various departments, statistics about the religious affiliation of Duke students, regulations and policies, and the Dean's welcome for the 1940-1941 school year.